Lakshman Kambam

UI/UX Designer & Web Developer at Esolvit Inc

klakshman318@gmail.com

Summary

I'm a passionate UI/UX designer & Web Developer., everyday learner with rare combination of Development(php) and Designing skills with creative thoughts which I developed best web portals based on eCommerce and networking. I worked on high quality designs with 4 years of experience in user interface and web development, I do understand user needs and translating those needs into a perfect visuals and easy to use products for web and mobile platform and I'm enthusiastic starter in developing web applications and always ready to grasp new tech knowledge.

Experience

UI/UX Designer & Web Developer at Esolvit Inc

December 2013 - Present (2 years 9 months)

I work as a UI/UX Designer and Web developer for Esolvit Inc, where I'm responsible for building web applications, UI design based on UX and maintaining company website.

Build Responsive web interface with HTML5, CSS3, AngularJS and Bootstrap.

Test and fix cross browser issues using web hacks.

Use AngularJS to handle complex business logic on front end.

Create animations to increase user experience by using CSS3 transition/3D Transform Methods.

Work with other .Net developers to deliver end to end web application with Entity Framework 6, .Net MVC, AngularJS and Bootstrap.

Trouble Shooting and Bug fixing for web applications.

UI Designer & Web Developer at Voice of Bigdata Solutions

June 2013 - November 2013 (6 months)

I worked as a UI Designer & web developer for Voice of Big data. where i am responsible for building web applications and maintaining company website.

Design web interface with HTML 5, CSS3 and JQuery.

Test and fix cross browser issues.

Template Design, Logo Design, banner, image with Adobe Suite(Photoshop, Flash, Illustrator).

UI Designer and Developer at Rudrasa

March 2013 - May 2013 (3 months)

Web Designer and Jr. web developer at Fonkr Solutions

September 2012 - February 2013 (6 months)

Design web interface with HTML 5, CSS3 and JQuery.

Expertise in Dreamweaver and Photoshop.

Worked with other PHP developers to learn end to end web application program with Framework, MySql DB and Logics.

Developed and maintained PHP applications.

Web Designer at Rudrasa

January 2012 - August 2012 (8 months)

Build web interface with HTML5, CSS3.

Test and fix cross browser issues.

Use Jquery to handle complex business logic on front end.

Create animations to increase user experience by using JQuery,Flash.

Jr. Web Designer at Acme Business Services

May 2011 - December 2011 (8 months)

Design Website UI with HTML, CSS.

Mock up, develop and adjust websites to meet different requirements from clients.

Template Design, Logo Design, banner, web ui, image with Adobe Suite(Photoshop, Dreamweaver, Flash).

Web Designer Fresher at XeonsoftSolutions

November 2010 - February 2011 (4 months)

Design Website UI with HTML, CSS.

Content Upload.

Mock up, develop and adjust websites to meet different requirements from clients.

Design Logo, banner, image with Adobe Suite(Photoshop, Flash) for clients.

Volunteer Experience

Traffic Survey Associate at Traffic & Transportation planning Services

May 2008 - July 2008

With the rapid pace of urbanisation, cities are emerging as potential markets and as a result large scale developments are in demand. Any such development can impact the surrounding roads by adding more vehicles to existing traffic or altering traffic patterns altogether. In addition to designing appropriate access for the proposed developments, planners and developers should strive to maintain a satisfactory level of transportation service and safety for all road users.

Traffic access and impact studies gather and analyze information that will help determine the need for any improvements to interior, adjacent, and nearby roadway systems.

Helpmate at Hyderabad International Machine Tool Expo at Hitex Exhibition Centre

May 2009 - July 2009

Languages

Telugu (Native or bilingual proficiency)

Hindi (Full professional proficiency)

English (Professional working proficiency)

Kannada (Elementary proficiency)

Skills & Expertise

JavaScript

HTML5

jQuery

CSS

PHP

Photoshop

User Experience

Web Development

Illustrator

MySQL

WordPress

Flash

XML

Responsive Web Design

AJAX

Dreamweaver

Flash Professional

Corel Draw

Adobe Illustrator

After Effects

PhoneGap

FTPS

GoDaddy

Windows Movie Maker

Windows 8.1

Web Applications

E-commerce

XHTML

Joomla

ActionScript

CMS

Software Installation

SEO

Adobe Creative Suite Bootstrap

Gaming

Education

Dr BR Ambedkar University Hyderabad

Bachelor's Degree, B.Com (Computers), 2012 - 2015

Grade: B

Activities and Societies: Education and Science Lab

Sharada High School

High School, SSC, 2004 - 2009

Grade: A

Activities and Societies: Quiz Competition, Karate, Cricket, Scholarship for 1st Rank

Interests

Technology | Animation Movies | Physics | Science | Playing Virtual Reality Games In Xbox and Playstation |
True Story Movies | Historical Stories | Chess | Cricket | Ruby Cube | Fanorona

Courses

Web Designer and Jr. web developer

Fonkr Solutions

PHP

Ajax

Javascript

UI/UX Designer & Web Developer

Esolvit Inc

Responsive Design

Independent Coursework

Design Techniques

Hardware Networking

Programming Techniques

Web Hacks

Organizations

Gana Technology Institute(Govt.)

Training in Multimedia

June 2010 to October 2010

Lakshman Kambam

UI/UX Designer & Web Developer at Esolvit Inc

klakshman318@gmail.com



1 person has recommended Lakshman

"Lakshman, is an incredible blend of HTML code genius, team empowerment, innovative design and UI/UX Web Developer at Esolvit, Inc. He is a great asset to Company and Esolvit product development team. I always enjoyed working with him. His thirst for knowledge and passion to learn more only propels each project that he works on. His mind is constantly thinking of the next best way to complete a task or meet a goal more effectively. As a young creative he also has an amazing ability to stay disciplined in enhancing his skills and staying focused on each task at hand. He is truly a leader in the next generation of out of the box creativity and problem solving."

— Usha Boddapu, CEO/Co-Founder, Esolvit Inc, managed Lakshman at Esolvit Inc

Contact Lakshman on LinkedIn